Execution is everything.
The Killer is a crime, thriller film directed by David Fincher.
After a fateful miss, an assassin battles his employers, and himself,
on an international manhunt he insists isn't personal.
The Killer, played by Michael Fassbender.
The Expert, played by Tilda Swinton.
The Lawyer - Hodges, played by Charles Parnell.
The Client - Claybourne, played by Arliss Howard.
Dolores, played by Kerry O'Malley.
Magdala, played by Sophie Charlotte.
The Killer is a 2023 American action thriller film directed by David
Fincher from a screenplay by Andrew Kevin Walker.
It is based on the French graphic novel series The Killer written by
Alexis "Matz" Nolent and illustrated by Luc Jacamon.
The film stars Michael Fassbender in the main role alongside Arliss Howard, Charles Parnell,
Kerry O'Malley, Sala Baker, Sophie Charlotte, and Tilda Swinton in supporting roles.
In the film, Fassbender plays an assassin who embarks on an
international vendetta after a hit goes wrong.
Development on the graphic novel adaptation began in November 2007, when Fincher was reported to direct the film with Alessandro Camon
writing the script, and Paramount Pictures and Plan B Entertainment, respectively, were hired to distribute and produce the film.
By February 2021, Fincher moved the project over to Netflix with Walker
replacing Camon as writer and Fassbender circling the lead role.
Swinton joined the cast that October, with filming beginning
the following month, and wrapped March 2022.
Filming locations included Paris, Dominican Republic,
and several places in the United States.
The Killer premiered at the 80th Venice International
Film Festival on September 3, 2023.
The film received a limited theatrical release on October 27
before streaming on Netflix on November 10.
The film received positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of sniper, new york city,
assassin, airport, paris, france.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.